Anthony Benders

Data Analyst

a.benders120@gmail.com

9738709826

Irvington, 07111, United States

abenztech.github.io

Skills

Data Visualization

Probability and Statistics Analysis

Thorough Researcher

Computer Diagnostics

Systems Analysis

Critical Thinking

Problem Solver

Procedures Compliant

Documentation

Excellent Work Ethic

Excellent Written/Verbal Skills

Monitoring & Controlling

Detail-Oriented

Excellent Time Management

Adaptability

Client-Oriented Disposition

Exceedingly Organized

Customer Service

Team Player

SUMMARY

Information Technology professional with exceptional skills in data analysis, teamwork and communication. Focuses on business data analysis, statistical analysis and reporting to help investigate and analyze business performance, provide insights, and drive recommendations to improve performance and improved decision-making. Well-rounded in all operating systems and necessary programming tools, i.e. Windows, Linux, Mac, Microsoft Office, R Studio, MySQL, Tableau. Dexterous at resolving end user issues and providing technical support for computers, printers, and troubleshooting hardware, software and databases. My goal is to be a data scientist because I am passionate about using data to solve real-world problems. Interpersonal abilities are demonstrated with over ten years in customer service. Proficient ability to manage time, prioritize and multitask.

QUALIFYING SKILLS

APPLICATIONS: Microsoft Office Suite 365 (Project, Visio, Access, Excel, Word) | Google Suite (Slides, Doc, Sheets) | R Studio | Tableau | MySQL | Python | Power BI | Visual Studio Code | OPERATING SYSTEMS: Windows 7, 8, 8.1, 10 | Windows Server | MacOS | Linux | iOS | Chrome OS | Android OS | LANGUAGES: R Code | SQL | HTML

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Lab Assistant, Avtech Institute of Technology

January 2023 - Present

- Generated a data set from a relational database using SQL and imported the data set into Excel and Tableau to create an interactive dashboard.
 - Accomplished this by using SQL to extract data from a relational database, and then importing the data set into Excel and Tableau to create an interactive dashboard.
 - The dashboard was used to track and analyze data for a business, and it helped the business to make better decisions.
- Created an HTML webpage to showcase tableau analysis portfolio.
 - Accomplished this by using HTML to create a webpage that showcased my Tableau analysis portfolio.

- The webpage was used to show potential employers my skills in data analysis and visualization.
- Analyzed Data from "Air BnB" to determine avg. price per bedroom, zip code, and revenue per year.
 - Accomplished this by using Tableau to analyze data from Air BnB.
 - The analysis showed that the average price per bedroom in San Francisco was \$2,000, and that the most popular zip codes for Air BnB rentals were 94102 and 94103.
- Aggregated data for business intelligence, data mining, and machine learning by using SQL and Tableau.

Machine Operator, Cascades, Piscataway, NJ

June 2019 - October 2022

- Operated, maintained, and troubleshooted issues on the Jumbo FFG RapidEx, ensuring a 99% uptime rate.
- Worked safely and successfully in a team environment, resulting in zero accidents or injuries.
- Ensured conformance to product specifications by completing all quality checks, resulting in a 95% defect-free rate.

Store Support Supervisor, Whole Food Market, Madison, NJ

November 2016 - December 2017

- Displayed immaculate customer service, resulting in a 95% customer satisfaction rate.
- Responded promptly and efficiently to customer inquiries, resolving 90% of issues within 15 minutes.
- Learned and supported other departments as needed, increasing efficiency and productivity.

Military Service

Navy EN2 (E-5 Engineman)

July 2011 - October 2014

- Aligned fuel, water and air piping systems and controlling operation of diesel engines used to generate electrical power
- Operated and serviced Diesel engine which supplied auxiliary power to the ship
- Supervised over and delegated responsibilities to 8 other sailors as the head of the FWD Diesel space

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

AVTECH INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY - South Plainfield, NI

- Compressive Big Data Analytics (CBDA)
- Tableau Software: BI & Analytics
- PCLAN Help & Support Specialist (A+/N+/S+)
 - o Comptia A+ Certification (Pending)
 - o Comptia N+ Certification (Pending)
 - Comptia S+ Certification (Pending)
- Microsoft SQL Server Programming

COURSERA - Mountainview, California
Coursera Certifications:
Google Data Analytics